<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<check status="enabled">
    <name><![CDATA[Portability Flaw: File Separator]]></name>
    <description><![CDATA[The use of hardcoded file separators causes portability problems.]]></description>
    <explanation><![CDATA[Different operating systems use different characters as file separators. For example, Microsoft Windows systems use "\", while UNIX systems use "/". When applications have to run on different platforms, the use of hardcoded file separators can lead to incorrect execution of application logic and potentially a denial of service.

Example 1: The following code uses a hardcoded file separator to open a file:

KF_CODE_EXAMPLE
...
os.open(directoryName + "\\" + fileName);
...]]></explanation>
    <severity>Medium</severity>
    <recommendations>Always test your code on any platform on which it is targeted to run on. 
Use os.sep as a separator in a path or os.path.join to join parts of the path</recommendations>
    <links><![CDATA[[1] Standards Mapping - Common Weakness Enumeration CWE ID 474
[2] Standards Mapping - DISA Control Correlation Identifier Version 2 CCI-001310
[3] Standards Mapping - Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard Version 3.0 Requirement 6.5.6
[4] Standards Mapping - Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard Version 3.1 Requirement 6.5.6
[5] Standards Mapping - Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard Version 3.2 Requirement 6.5.6
[6] Standards Mapping - Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard Version 3.2.1 Requirement 6.5.6
[7] Standards Mapping - Payment Card Industry Software Security Framework 1.0 Control Objective 4.2 - Critical Asset Protection
[8] Standards Mapping - Payment Card Industry Software Security Framework 1.1 Control Objective 4.2 - Critical Asset Protection
[9] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.1 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
[10] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.2 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
[11] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.3 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
[12] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.4 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
[13] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.5 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
[14] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.6 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
[15] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.7 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
[16] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.8 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
[17] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.9 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
[18] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.10 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
[19] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.11 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
[20] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 5.1 APSC-DV-002520 CAT II
]]></links>
    <patterns>
        <pattern_simple>
            <string operator="eq">\</string>
        </pattern_simple>
    </patterns>
</check>
