<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<check status="enabled">
    <name><![CDATA[Insecure Deployment: Non Production Ready]]></name>
    <description><![CDATA[The application contains a component that is not designed to be deployed on a production environment.]]></description>
    <explanation><![CDATA[The Django application exposes the serve view of the static files application which is not designed to be deployed in a production environment. According to Django documentation:

"The static files tools are mostly designed to help with getting static files successfully deployed into production. This usually means a separate, dedicated static file server, which is a lot of overhead to mess with when developing locally. Thus, the staticfiles app ships with a quick and dirty helper view that you can use to serve files locally in development.

This view will only work if DEBUG is True.

That's because this view is grossly inefficient and probably insecure. This is only intended for local development, and should never be used in production."]]></explanation>
    <severity>Low</severity>
    <recommendations>Remove a non-production code from the application before deployment</recommendations>
    <links><![CDATA[[1] Django Foundation The staticfiles app (https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/ref/contrib/staticfiles/)
[2] Django Foundation Managing static files (https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/howto/static-files/)
[3] Standards Mapping - DISA Control Correlation Identifier Version 2 CCI-000381
[4] Standards Mapping - General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) Indirect Access to Sensitive Data
[5] Standards Mapping - Payment Card Industry Software Security Framework 1.0 Control Objective 10.2 - Threat and Vulnerability Management
[6] Standards Mapping - Payment Card Industry Software Security Framework 1.1 Control Objective 10.2 - Threat and Vulnerability Management
[7] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.1 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
[8] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.2 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
[9] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.3 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
[10] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.4 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
[11] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.5 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
[12] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.6 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
[13] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.7 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
[14] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.8 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
[15] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.9 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
[16] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.10 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
[17] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 4.11 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
[18] Standards Mapping - Security Technical Implementation Guide Version 5.1 APSC-DV-001500 CAT II
]]></links>
    <patterns>
        <pattern_simple>
            <attribute>django.contrib.staticfiles.views.serve</attribute>
        </pattern_simple>
        <pattern_simple>
            <function_call>
                <name operator="eq">django.contrib.staticfiles.views.serve</name>
            </function_call>
        </pattern_simple>
    </patterns>
</check>
